Guide to the Herman F. Mark Collection RG.002
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series VI: Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn and the Polymer Research Institute, 6473
  - Subseries A: Mark Birthday Symposia and Festschrift, 6474
    - "Portrait of a Scientist: Twenty minutes of time in his office" by L. Schleiniger, 1976 January; 9362 (Box 20, Item 1)
    - Birthday gift "Natur und Architektur", 1985; 9352 (Box 20, Item 2)
    - Birthday wishes from Mayor Koch (bound), 1985 May 6; 9353 (Box 20, Item 3)
    - Birthday wishes from The Association of Finnish Chemical Societies (bound), 1985 May 3; 9355 (Box 20, Item 4)
    - Grosse Goldene Ehrenzeichen mit dem Stern [Great Golden medal with Star] awarded by the Republic of Austria (in red binder with gold seal), 1985 April 22; 9357 (Box 20, Item 5)
    - 70th Birthday Celebration photo album, 1965 May; 9361 (Box 20, Item 6)
    - "Perspective in Polymer Science: A Volume dedicated to Herman F. Mark on the occasion of his 70th birthday" ed. E. Proskauer, E. Immergut, C. Overberger, 1966; 9363 (Box 20, Item 7)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from The Polish Academy of Sciences: Centre of Molecular and Marcomolecular Studies (bound), 1985 April 12; 9356 (Box 20, Item 8)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from Die Österreichische Akademie der Wissenschaften [the Austrian Academy of Sciences], 1985 May 3; 9354 (Box 20, Item 9)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Chinese Chemical Society member and former student Qian Baogong, 1985; 9358 (Box 20, Item 10)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Chinese Chemical Society President Qian Renyuan, 1985 May; 9359 (Box 20, Item 11)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Chinese Chemical Society member Liu Dagang, 1985 May; 9360 (Box 20, Item 12)
    - 90th Birthday Festschrift from the Institute of Macromolecular Chemistry, Czechoslovak Academy of Science, 1985; 9365 (Box 20, Item 13)
    - "Polymer Science in the Next Decade: An International Symposium Honoring Herman F. Mark on his 90th Birthday" ed. O Vogl and E. Immergut, 1987; 9364 (Box 20, Item 14)
  - Subseries B: Mark Memorial Symposium and Scholarship Fund, 6475
    - Memorial Symposium planning materials (including photographs), 1992; 9531 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Symposium planning materials (S.M. Atlas), 1992; 9532 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Symposium "Polymers to the Year 2000 and Beyond" programs and booklets, 1992; 9533 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Symposium invitation lists and registration forms, 1992; 9534 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Symposium invitation lists and registration forms, 1992; 9535 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Symposium invitations and registration forms, 1992; 9536 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Symposium fax confirmation slips, 1992; 9537 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Mark Scholarship Fund donor lists, 1992; 9540 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Mark Scholarship Fund donor lists, 1992; 9538 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Mark Symposium and Fund thank you lists, 1992; 9541 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Memorial Symposium manuscripts and Wiley correspondence, 1992; 9539 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Subseries C: Events, 6469
    - Polymer Research Institute Symposia programs, 1949-1989; 1949-1966; 9542 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Symposia brochures, 1948-1967; 9543 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Symposium-Workshop, "Polymeric Materials and their use in Transportation," and project proposals, 1976-1977; 9571 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - "Polymer Synthesis in the 1980s" Symposium and Honorary Degree awarded to Prof. Carl S. Marvel, 9572 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Symposium in Memorial of Professor Aharon Katzir-Katchalsky, 1973 February 3; 9573 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Event Programs, 1966-1968; 9574 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Subseries D: News and Brochures, 9011
    - PRI and Polytechnic public relations, 1961-2003; 1961-1968; 9580 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Press Releases, 1960-1966; 9584 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Report from Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1955-1956; 9581 (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Polytechnic in Brief and Polytechnic News, 1968-2003; 9582 (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - The Polytechnic Faculty News, 1957-1971; 1965-1971; 9583 (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - PRI and Polytechnic brochures, 1960s - 2000s; 9585 (Box 21, Folder 23)
- Series VII: Photographs, 6477
  - Subseries A: Portraits, 9586
    - Herman Mark in Austrian officer's uniform, World War I, undated; 9609 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Herman Mark in Rogers Hall office, undated; 9614 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits, undated; 9610 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits, undated; 9611 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits, undated; 9612 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Herman Mark color portraits, undated; 9613 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Herman Mark silhouette portrait, undated; 9615 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits with contact sheet, undated; 9616 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Herman Mark color portrait contact sheet, 1975; 9617 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Herman Mark black and white portraits with negatives, undated; 9618 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Herman Mark portrait photocopies, undated; 9619 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Herman Mark Oversize portrait, undated; 9678 (Box 30, Item 1)
  - Subseries B: Family and Friends, 9587
    - Portraits and group photos, 1927-1929; undated; 9620 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Family portrait reproductions (photograph, slide, photocopy), undated; 9621 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Group military portrait and negative, undated; 9622 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Maria Mark (Mimi), 1938; undated; 9623 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Herman and Maria Mark with friends, 1953, 1958; 9624 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Hans Mark, Peter Mark, and Mark grandchildren, undated; 14817 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Herman Mark with grandson Rufus and family, 1990; 9627 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Family and Friends, 1990s; 9625 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Family and Friends in Texas, 1990s; 9626 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Subseries C: Students and Colleagues, 9591
    - Israeli President Ephraim Katzir, 1976; undated; 9631 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Professor Frederick Eirich, undated; 9632 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Professor Murray Goodman, 1974 January 17; 9633 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Dr. Jack B. Nagler (former student), 1991 August 27; 9634 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Lingyu He (visiting scholar), 1990; 9635 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Bruno Zimm and Paul Doty, 1990; 9636 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Mark in his office and lab with colleagues, 1980s; 9637 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Professional associates, undated; 14818 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Mark with Students (includes negatives), undated; 9638 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Subseries D: Events, 9589
    - Herman Mark Bust dedication, with sculptor Jimilu Mason, 1959; 9604 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - American Chemical Society meetings, 1968, undated; 9629 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Willard Gibbs Medal, 1975; 9605 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - National Medal of Science, with President Jimmy Carter, 1979; 9602 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Wolf Prize, 1979; 9607 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Heity Foundation Dinner, 1991; 9630 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 100 Shares of Montecatini stock to PIB, undated; 9606 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 80th Birthday Celebration contact sheets, 1975; 9628 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - 90th Birthday Celebration, 1985; 9601 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Birthday Celebrations, miscellaneous, undated; 9598 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Polyethylene Demonstration, undated; 9603 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Lectures, undated; 9608 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Events, miscellaneous (black and white), 1947-1986; 9600 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Events, miscellaneous (color), 1983; undated; 9599 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous, 9640
    - Travels, 1956-1966, 9641 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Travels, 1980-1984, 9642 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Mountains, undated; 9643 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Herman and Maria Mark's gravestone, 1992; 9644 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - NASA, 1976-1982; 9645 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Subseries F: Negatives, 9639
    - Negatives, undated; 9646 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Negatives, undated; 9647 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Subseries G: Albums, 9590
    - OMV Aktiengesellschaft, undated; 9648 (Box 23.5, Item 1)
    - Award reception, undated; 9649 (Box 23.5, Item 2)
    - Poly event, undated; 9650 (Box 23.5, Item 3)
  - Subseries H: Slides, undated; 9850
    - Bio, undated; 9869 (Box 24, Object 1)
    - CGO, undated; 9860 (Box 24, Object 2)
    - China, undated; 9852 (Box 24, Object 3)
    - China CCCP, undated; 9858 (Box 24, Object 4)
    - Comfort, undated; 9861 (Box 24, Object 5)
    - Comp, undated; 9868 (Box 24, Object 6)
    - Fibers Res., undated; 9865 (Box 24, Object 7)
    - For Peter 80th, undated; 9851 (Box 24, Object 8)
    - Herman K (empty box), undated; 9859 (Box 24, Object 9)
    - [illegible] History USA, undated; 9856 (Box 24, Object 10)
    - Luiz Schleiniger- Photographer, undated; 9863 (Box 24, Object 11)
    - Medical, undated; 9854 (Box 24, Object 12)
    - Medical Reserve, undated; 9855 (Box 24, Object 13)
    - Novophalt, undated; 9864 (Box 24, Object 14)
    - Perkin Ivitrene, 9867 (Box 24, Object 15)
    - Peter Color, 1958; 9866 (Box 24, Object 16)
    - Photos, undated; 9857 (Box 24, Object 17)
    - Supra, undated; 9853 (Box 24, Object 18)
    - Synthetic Paper, undated; 9862 (Box 24, Object 19)
- Series VIII: Framed photographs and documents, 7531
  - Subseries A: Framed Items, 14819
    - The Jabotinsky Centennial Medal, 1980-11-11; 14820 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 1)
    - 30 Years of International Cellulose Research Limited, 1969; 14821 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 2)
    - International Award in Plastics Science and Engineering, 1962 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 3)
    - Tree Dedication Certificate, 1983 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 4)
    - Journal of Polymer Research replica of cover of inaugural issue, 1985 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 5)
    - Family Crest, undated (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 6)
    - German Certificate, 1970 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 7)
    - Quarter Century Service Scroll, undated (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 8)
    - Society of Plastics Engineers, Inc. Member Emeritus, 1959 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 9)
    - Polymer Education Award, 1982 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 10)
    - Honorary Membership to The Fiber Society, 1965 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 11)
    - Division of Polymer Chemistry Award, 1982 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 12)
    - 80th Birthday Plaque from Polytechnic Institute, 1975 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 13)
    - Division of Cellulose Chemistry, 1959 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 14)
    - The Seventh Annual Plastics Planning Conference Distinguished Speaker Plaque, 1981 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 15)
    - Perkin Medal Award from the American Section of the Society of Chemical Industry, 1980 (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 16)
    - Bravery Medal in 1st World War for Most Decorated Officer, undated (Bin Frame Rack 1, Item 17)
    - Image of soldiers, undated (Bin Folder Rack 6, Item 1)
    - Map of China, undated (Bin Folder Rack 6, Item 2)
    - Framed butterfly, undated (Bin Folder Rack 6, Item 3)
    - Half-Million Miler 100,000 Mile Club, undated (Bin Folder Rack 6, Item 4)
    - Prof Ddr. Hermann Mark 25 Janner 1987, 1987-01-25 (Bin Folder Rack 6, Item 5)
    - Photograph of Herman Mark in small gold frame, undated (Box 38, Item 3)
    - Photograph of four men, undated (Box 38, Item 4)
    - Photograph of Herman Mark with two women, undated (Box 38, Item 5)
    - Ronald Reagan photograph in Johnson Space Center, 1981-11-13 (Box 38, Item 6)
    - Herman Mark with unknown man photograph, undated (Box 38, Item 7)
    - Group photograph from the Gordon Research Conference on Polymers, 1965-02-01-1965-02-05 (Box 38, Item 8)
    - Herman Mark graduation group photograph with JFK, 1961 (Box 38, Item 9)
  - Subseries B: Unframed Items
    - Dark wooden box HFM, Undated (Box 39)
    - Scroll holder with Greek lettering, Undated (Box 39)
    - Decorative wooden box, Undated (Box 39)
    - Stone candle holder, Undated (Box 39)
    - Stefan Meyer medal, Undated (Box 39)
    - Herman F. Mark empty folder, Undated (Box 39)
    - Technion-Israel Institute of Technology and The American Technion Society Harvey Prize, 1976-06-23 (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Technion Israel Institute of Technology Honorary Degree, 1975-06-04 (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Universitas Carolina Pragensis Honorary Degree, 1965-08-30 (Bin Map Case 1)
    - S.Miluera Artwork, 1975-04-15 (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Portrait by Mimi Mark, Undated (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Portrait by Mimi Mark 1957 (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Portrait by Mimi Mark 1957 (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Portrait by Mimi Mark, Undated (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Portrait by Mimi Mark, Undated (Bin Map Case 1)
    - Mountain Landscape, 1983-08 (Box 31, Item 1)
    - Photograph of Herman Mark with Herman Rudorfer, 1980-05 (Box 31, Item 2)
    - Herman Mark Children Photographs, undated (Box 31, Item 3)
    - Charles Overberger photograph dedicated to GHR, undated (Box 31, Item 4)
    - Unknown man photograph, undated (Box 31, Item 5)
    - Group photograph from Herman Mark's visit to India's National Chemical Labratory, 1965-04-25 (Box 31, Item 6)
    - Herman Mark photograph, undated (Box 31, Item 7)
    - Murray portrait dedicated to GHR, undated (Box 31, Item 8)
    - Herman Mark Portrait, undated (Box 31, Item 9)
    - Schlofshof au Heidelberg Photograph, undated (Box 31, Item 10)
    - Professor illustration, 1982-05 (Box 31, Item 11)
    - Unknown woman portrait, undated (Box 31, Item 12)
    - Unknown man portrait, undated (Box 31, Item 13)
    - Herman Mark Portrait, undated (Box 31, Item 14)
    - General Electric Certificate in Modern Engineering Fall 1962 (Box 32, Item 1)
    - General Electric Certificate in Modern Engineering Spring 1963 (Box 32, Item 2)
    - The American Chemical Society Award in Polymer Chemistry, 1965-04-05 (Box 32, Item 3)
    - IBM Update '77 Recognition of Participation, 1977-07-31-1977-08-26 (Box 32, Item 4)
    - Plastics Institute of America Recognition, 1965-01-22 (Box 32, Item 5)
    - Commissioning of Kentucky Colonel from Governor Brown, 1983-03-03 (Box 32, Item 6)
    - The Olney Medal of the American Association of Textile Chemists and Colorists, 1965 (Box 32, Item 7)
    - Russian Certificate, 1966 (Box 32, Item 8)
    - Charles Goodyear Medal from American Chemical Society, 1988 (Box 32, Item 9)
    - The Elliott Cresson Medal of the Franklin Institute, 1966-10-19 (Box 32, Item 10)
    - Certificate of Appreciation from Council of Long Island Technical Societies, 1963-05-07 (Box 33, Item 1)
    - Wayne State University College of Engineering and Division of Urban Extension Certificate, Summer 1968 (Box 33, Item 2)
    - VOK German Certificate, 1981-12-15 (Box 33, Item 3)
    - Sarnia Lecture in Science of the Chemical Institute of Canada, 1967-01-11 (Box 33, Item 4)
    - Consortium Officinae Chemicae Celeberrimae Certificate, undated (Box 33, Item 5)
    - The Wolf Foundation Prize in Chemistry, 1979 (Box 33, Item 6)
    - Croatian Certificate, 1974 (Box 33, Item 7)
    - The National Medal of Science, 1979 (Box 33, Item 8)
    - Ceskoslovenska Akademie Ved Certificate, 1988 (Box 33, Item 9)
    - Father of Polymer Chemistry Certificate from the American Chemical Society, 1985-05-03 (Box 34, Item 1)
    - The International Academy of Wood Science Fellowship Award, 1968-07-02 (Box 34, Item 2)
    - Distinguished Lecture Award from University of Massachusetts, 1984-01 (Box 34, Item 3)
    - National Institute of Sciences of India Honorary Fellowship Award, 1960-12 (Box 34, Item 4)
    - Chemical Pioneer Award from the American Institute of Chemists, 1972-05-20 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - The Albert A. Michelson Edward W. Morley Award, 1989-04-28 (Box 34, Item 6)
    - Certificate from Israel Plastic Society, 1975-07-13 (Box 34, Item 7)
    - CIRFS Certificate, 1980-09 (Box 34, Item 8)
    - Technik und angewandte Naturwissenschaften from Aachener und Munchener Pries, 1975-06-23 (Box 34, Item 9)
    - Russian Certificate, 1974 (Box 34, Item 10)
    - Doctor of Science Degree from University of Nottingham, 1980-07-10 (Box 35, Item 1)
    - Universite Claude Bernard Honorary Doctorate, 1987-09-15 (Box 35, Item 2)
    - El Rector Magnifico de la Universidad Autonoma de Madrid Honorary Doctorate, 1973-06-25 (Box 35, Item 3)
    - Universitas Longinsvlanae Doctor of Science, 1976-06-11 (Box 35, Item 4)
    - Die Technische Hochschule Munchen Honorary Doctor of Natural Sciences, 1960-02-24 (Box 35, Item 5)
    - Das Gesamtkollegium Der Technische Hochschule In Wein Honorary Doctor of Natural Sciences, 1964-11-11 (Box 35, Item 6)
    - Institutul Politehnic Iasi Honorary Doctorate, 1972-10-16 (Box 35, Item 7)
    - Institutul Politehnic "Gh. Asachi" Din Iasi Honorary Doctorate, 1971-05-29 (Box 35, Item 8)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Honorary Doctorate, 1965-06-09 (Box 35, Item 9)
    - University of Massachusetts Honorary Doctorate Paper, 1982-07-12 (Box 35, Item 10)
    - University of Massachusetts Honorary Doctorate, 1982-07-12 (Box 35, Item 11)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science Fifty Year Membership Certificate, 1989-07-28 (Box 36, Item 1)
    - The National Register of Prominent Americas and International Notables Certificate, 1978-1979 (Box 36, Item 2)
    - The New York Academy of Sciences Honorary Life Membership, undated (Box 36, Item 3)
    - The New York Academy of Sciences Honorary Life Membership 1977, 1977-12-08 (Box 36, Item 4)
    - Honorary Membership to the Chemists Club of New York, 1976-12-29 (Box 36, Item 5)
    - National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America Membership Certificate, 1961-04-25 (Box 36, Item 6)
    - Plastics Institute of America Membership Certificate, 1965-01-22 (Box 36, Item 7)
    - The American Institute of Chemists Life Fellowship Certificate, 1978-04-13 (Box 36, Item 8)
    - Honorary Membership to the Society for the Chemical Industry, 1980-10-29 (Box 36, Item 9)
    - Japanese Certificate, 1972-05-25 (Box 36, Item 10)
    - Austrian Academy of Science Honorary Membership of the Mathmatical and Natural Science Class, 1970-05-26 (Box 36, Item 11)
    - Polytechnic University Establishment of the Alstadt, Lord, Mark Chair in the Natural Sciences, 1989-02-21 (Box 36, Item 12)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York President's Associates Membership, 1982-10-06 (Box 36, Item 13)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Presentation of Bust, 1960-03-12 (Box 36, Item 14)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Presentation of Bust, 1960-03-12 (Box 36, Item 15)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn Retirement Letter, 1965-06-03 (Box 36, Item 16)
    - Wiener Beiting May 3, 1895 Copy, undated (Box 37, Item 1)
    - The New York Times May 3, 1895 Copy, undated (Box 37, Item 2)
    - The White House Correspondence from Ronald Reagan, 1985-04-24 (Box 37, Item 3)
    - Polytechnic Institute of New York Certificate of Appreciation, 1974-05-03 (Box 37, Item 4)
    - 80th Birthday Recognition from the Polish Academy of Science, 1975 (Box 37, Item 5)
    - 80th Birthday Recognition from Cristofor Simionescu, 1975 (Box 37, Item 6)
    - 80th Birthday Recognition from S.R. Palit from High Polymer Laboratory at IACS, 1975-04-15 (Box 37, Item 7)
    - 80th Birthday Recognition from Specialist Group for Macromolecular Chemistry, 1975 (Box 37, Item 8)
    - 80th Birthday Recognition from IUPAC Symposium on Macromolecules, 1975 (Box 37, Item 9)
    - Charles Goodyear Medal from American Chemical Society, 1988 (Box 38, Item 1)
    - Wooden plaque backing, undated (Box 38, Item 2)
  - Subseries C: Needs Conservation
    Conditions Governing Access
    Items in this subseries need conservation and have limited access.
    - ICRFS (International Conference on Research Frontiers in Sciences), Undated (Bin Cart)
    - Framed medal from Republic of France, Undated (Bin Cart)
    - The Society of the Sigma XI of the Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn 1970 (Bin Cart)
    - 90th Birthday Plaque from Graduate Students in Chemistry 1985 (Bin Cart)
    - Circular mirror, Undated (Bin Cart)
    - Blue fringe hat, Undated (Bin Cart)
    - Box full of photograph slides, Undated (Bin Cart)
    - Polymer Paperweight, Undated (Bin Cart)
    - Wooden clock with world map, Undated (Bin Cart)
    - Gold metal clock, Undated (Bin Cart)
- Series IX: Magnetic Media, 2990
  - Subseries A: Video tapes: Interviews and Ceremonies, 2961
    - American Chemical Society Interview with Dr. Herman F. Mark, Dr. Charles Overberger, interviewer (part 1 of 2), 1981; 2962; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 1)
    - American Chemical Society Interview with Dr. Herman F. Mark, Dr. Charles Overberger, interviewer (part 2 of 2), 1981; 2963; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 2)
    - Eminent Chemists: H. Mark Interviewed by C. Overberger (part 1 of 2), undated; 2964; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 3)
    - Eminent Chemists Videotape Series: Dr. Herman F. Mark, undated; 6320; U-matic Runtime 46:10 (Box 25, Object 4)
      To view the digitized video, contact the Poly Archives.
    - H. Mark Interviewed by C. Overberger (part 2 of 2), undated; 2965; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 5)
    - Herman Mark, undated; 2966; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 6)
      tape length
      00:56:45
    - Presidential Ceremony Honoring the 1979 Medal of Science Awardees, 1980 January 14; 6321; U-matic Run time: approximately 20 minutes (Box 25, Object 7)
  - Subseries B: Video Tapes: Polymer Research, 2968
    - The Development of Early Polymer Chemistry in America -- The Early Years: Carl S. Marvel, 1980; 2970; Umatic tape (Box 25, Object 8)
    - MRS - Frontiers in Materials Research: Recent Advances in Polymers - H. Mark, 1989; 2969; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 9)
    - Polymer Science: Visions and Perspectives 1 of 2, 1999; 2971; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 10)
    - Polymer Science: Visions and Perspectives 2 of 2, 1999; 2978; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 11)
    - H. Mark PRI [Polymer Research Institute], undated; 2967; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 12)
      00:07:00
  - Subseries C: Video tapes: Scientific Topics, 2972
    - Herman Mark: Early 20th Century Physics (1), Probably 1979; 2973; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 13)
    - Herman Mark: Fibers (3), 1979; 2974; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 14)
    - Herman Mark: Rubber (4), 1979; 2975; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 15)
    - Herman Mark: Polymers and the Environment (5), 1979; 2976; VHS tapes (Box 25, Object 16)
    - Herman F. Mark: Aviation - Fire, 1983; 2977; VHS tape (Box 25, Object 17)
  - Subseries D: 3M Magnetic Tapes, 9680
    - Polymers Part III, 1968 March 9; 9681 (Box 26, Object 1)
    - H. Mark Polymers, undated; 9682 (Box 26, Object 2)
    - H. Mark Polymers, undated; 9683 (Box 26, Object 3)
  - Subseries E: Audio tapes and 740 diskettes, 9684
    - Lord Corporation's Symposium tapes, 1989 October 3-4; 9685 (Box 26, Object 4)
    - "Dimensions in Science" American Chemical Society, circa 1985; 9875 (Box 26, Object 5)
    - Mark II, undated; 9877 (Box 26, Object 6)
    - Mark III, undated; 9876 (Box 26, Object 7)
    - Unlabeled, undated; 9878 (Box 26, Object 8)
    - H. Mark 740 diskette (Scotch 3M), undated; 9686 (Box 26, Object 9)
    - Mark 740 diskette (IBM), undated; 9687 (Box 26, Object 10)
    - Chemistry Mark 740 diskette (IBM), undated; 9688 (Box 26, Object 11)
- Series X: Personal items and Miscellaneous, 9651
  - Subseries A: Desk drawer realia, 6478
    - Portable 3-Dimensional Joke Kit (actually contains spices), undated; 9655 (Box 27, Object 1)
    - Fulton Rubber Type Outift, undated; 9656 (Box 27, Object 2)
    - ABC rubber stamp kit, undated; 9659 (Box 27, Object 3)
    - North America Steel Company magnifying glass, 9660 (Box 27, Object 4)
    - Set of three keys, undated; 9661 (Box 27, Object 5)